KATHLEEN MERCADO

201-978-8617 | kathleenmerc@gmail.com | https://kathleenmercado.vercel.app https://www.linkedin.com/in/kathleenmercado | https://github.com/kathleenmerc

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Driven by a passion for emerging technologies and lifelong learning, I am actively pursuing a software engineer role. With 5+ years of healthcare experience, I bring a unique perspective and valuable skills in problem-solving, analytical thinking, attention to detail, and effective communication. Committed to collaboration, excellence, and constant growth, I am eager to join a team that shares these values and make a meaningful impact.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Front-End: HTML, CSS, JavaScript (Vanilla JS, ES6), TypeScript, React.js, Next.js, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, WordPress, Figma, DOM Manipulation
- Back-End: Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Google Firebase & Firestore, REST APIs, Object Oriented Programming
- Version Control: Git, GitHub, Gitpod, Visual Studio Code
- Additional Tools: Electronic Medical Records (EMR/EHR), Google Workspace, Microsoft Office, Trello

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer (Contract Position) | Nexus Technologies Group, LLC.

March 2023 - April 2023

- Designed and built a WordPress website for a Jamaican restaurant, while coordinating with the client to understand project specifications, integrate their brand voice, and successfully meet their launch timeline.
- Collaborated with a team of 3 developers to create a responsive website aimed at boosting traffic and online orders.
- Improved communication and workflow efficiency with Microsoft Teams and Trello.

Physical Therapist | Ivy Rehab Physical Therapy & Pivot Physical Therapy

Nov 2018 - Oct 2021

- Utilized data analysis to track patient progress, identify trends, and make data-driven decisions that led to a 25% reduction in treatment duration and readmission rates.
- Quickly adapted to new healthcare technologies and displayed a strong aptitude for learning new technical skills, saving 25% on administrative time and improving workflow.
- Applied problem-solving skills to develop tailored treatment plans, demonstrating analytical thinking and attention to detail, resulting in overall improvements in patient outcomes and retention.

EDUCATION

Per Scholas | Computer Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp

Sept 2022 - Jan 2023

• Successfully completed a full stack software development program, achieving a 99.63% final grade, where I gained proficiency in the MERN stack, JavaScript, and computer science concepts.

Design Lab | *UX Foundations: Visual and UI Design Course for Beginners*

May 2022 - Aug 2022

• Designed responsive screens, icons, and logos in Figma incorporating visual design elements, user interface design principles, empathy for users, and user accessibility concepts with the goal of optimizing user experience.

Northeastern University - Boston, MA

- Doctor of Physical Therapy (DPT)
- Bachelor of Science (BS) in Rehabilitation Science, Cum Laude

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

Web Application - Recipe Finder: Link | Code

- Solo project | JavaScript, React, MongoDB, Node.js, Express.js, CSS3, JSON Web Token
- Designed and built a full-stack web app for ingredient-based recipe searches using the MERN stack.
- Implemented full CRUD operations, JWT user authentication, HTTP requests, and React hooks.

Mobile Application - TherapEase: Link | Code

- Team project | TypeScript, Next.js, Google Firebase & Firestore, Tailwind CSS, Figma
- Collaborated with a team of 4 developers to create an app to enhance the appointment scheduling process for patients and physical therapists.
- Implemented Agile work methodologies and pair programming using tools such as Trello, Discord, and VS Code Live Share and produced low-fidelity wireframes in Figma to meet user needs.

2D Game - The Helicopter Game: Link | Code

- Solo project | HTML5, HTML Canvas, CSS3, Vanilla JavaScript
- Recreated the classic Helicopter Game with new features such as 1 or 2-player modes, player lives, and high score functionality.
- Included use of classes, objects, DOM manipulation, local storage, event listeners, and flexbox.